# Adam Tolbert

(404)-725-1574 | aotolbert@gmail.com | Github: https://github.com/aotolbert | Profile: https://www.aotolbert.com

## **Summary of Qualifications:**

I am a Certified Full Stack Web Developer & Certified Salesforce Admin specializing in developing real-time data integrations through a variety of techniques. This includes, (but is not limited to) SQLServer, scheduled and bulkified API calls, leveraging the Salesforce ecosystem's connections to third party data stores, as well as architecting and implementing ETL/CDC (Change Data Capture) tools. I am well-versed in developing within Salesforce frontend frameworks (LWC, Visualforce, Aura) and connecting them to the Apex and SOQL/SOSL backend and visa-versa. Working in fast paced environments, and adjusting to a constantly changing world, I am capable of maintaining high levels of energy and adapting quickly to any work environment that the situation demands. My strengths include organization, responsiveness, critical thinking, multi-tasking, data analytics, development design, knowledge acquisition, cooperation, and negotiation.

#### **Skills & Abilities**

#### **PROGRAMMING**

I am fluent in Apex Development, Salesforce Platform Development (Flows & Process Builder), SOQL, SOSL, Apex Unit Testing, Visualforce, LWC & Aura Components, JavaScript, ES5 and ES6, CSS, JQuery, BootStrap, REST/SOAP APIs, React.js, Ajax, Postman, Handlebars, JSON, ETL/CDC Tools, mvSQL, PostgreSQL, SQL Server, MongoDB, Node.js, Express.js, Heroku, and GoogleCloud Services.

#### **LEADERSHIP**

After about 6 months my role as Software Developer for Skyline Steel, I was given the responsibility to act as the development liaison between for my company, and a third party we contracted development work out to to keep up when the development demand outpaced what I was able to provide as the single inhouse software developer. I enjoyed taking on an active role in the development of the multitude of different applications, and felt personally responsible for the outcomes of the many projects despite having only minor influences on the actual code written on their particular applications.

#### **COMMUNICATION**

Working as a salesperson in logistics as my first job out of college led to communication being hard coded into the way I operate. Rapid and accurate communication is vital in every industry. I worked for over 2 years making sure that both colleagues and clients were informed as quickly as possible to maximize the companies potential and maintain customer relationships in an intrinsically uncertain industry such as logistics.

## **Experience**

#### SALESFORCE DEVELOPER | SKYLINE STEEL | APRIL 2019 - CURRENT

- As a new developer, I started by working alongside one other person to implement Salesforce within the company. I came in late in the implementation planning and was tasked developing some smaller custom integrations that were business/sales specific requests. We were able to go live in June of 2019 and once we had a working org with over 100 active users, my job shifted to building apps, jobs, triggers, anything that would allow the data to flow between our very new Salesforce org, and our very old ERP so that the data available to the users would be robust and accurate.
- I spent the past year or more designing, developing, and implementing a real time data integration between multiple different systems. I utilized a CDC tool to subscribe to specific types of data changes in the ERP which would automatically reflect those changes on a controlled SQLServer instance where I had scripts that would clear/reformat the data and then redirect the clean data to Salesforce. In Salesforce I coded a number of triggers and classes that would force each new record to attempt to locate construct references on itself to all it's associated records (Contact, Account, Salesperson\_c, etc) using keys generated in the intermediary database.

• A major hurdle of this was convincing the users to take a the additional steps, above and beyond their current sales cycle, in the name of data integrity. This involved creating appealing, functional, and rapid user interfaces for the sales people to manage their quote data in Salesforce. Then, as soon as the customer committed, a custom wizard would generate specifically for that quote, quickly validate all the necessary information was present, allow them to quickly remedy one of the 50+ potential errors, and then construct a nested series of API calls to our external ERP where the data would be inserted and passed on to the next team in the sales process.

#### NETWORK TECHNICIAN | GLS | AUGUST 2018 - APRIL 2019

- Proactively and reactively monitor the health of the network within multiple businesses and their franchises across the country. From over the phone troubleshooting, to using ssh to remote into systems to reconfigure devices, to scheduling onsite smart-hands.
- Coordinate the solutions of many different types of problems to the affected site, local tech dispatchers, the ISP, the company's IT administrators, and any other relevant parties to fix any connectivity issues as quickly and painlessly as possible.
- Constantly monitor the proactive monitoring system to ensure that any tickets that are generated either by a network health monitoring scraper or by user call-in, are responded to within 30 minutes and the actions are documented carefully so that the next technician can understand the issues and perform relevant tasks.

#### FREIGHT BROKER | NTG | IUNE 2016 - APRIL 2018

- Was responsible for the creation of over \$1MM worth of billing that resulted in over \$120,000 in total profit for the company.
- Oversaw both national and international shipments throughout the US and Canada and was responsible for ensuring a safe delivery in a timely manner. This involved a need for constant communication and rapid problem solving with multiple parties to provide the highest level of customer service to the client and to the carriers that we contracted.

#### BARISTA | JITTERY JOES | JUNE 2013 - APRIL 2016

- Maintain a positive disposition and a pleasant atmosphere for all customers while taking and assembling complex orders quickly and correctly.
- Ensured all the coffee bars and stations were always clean and fully stocked to increase the productivity
  of all the employees and to enhance the experience that the customers have when they go to gather their
  order.
- Coordinate with other Jittery Joe's franchises in order to complete bulk orders or restock products that were depleted and/or understaffed in order to keep with demand across all of Jittery Joe's many locations.

### **Education**

#### BACHELOR OF SCIENCE | MAY, 2016 | PRESBYTERIAN COLLEGE

- Major: Business Administration Management
- Study Abroad: Madrid, Spain (Universidad Francisco de Vitoria) Fall 2014

#### FULL STACK DEVELOPER CERTIFICATE | DECEMBER, 2018 | UNC-CHARLOTTE

• 6 Months (12 hours a week min.) of coding/programming education. Starting from the basics of the internet to writing, hosting, updating, expanding, and debugging full stack web applications, this class built foundational knowledge for most of the languages used by developers in today's world.